

CARINA

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT LEAD

CONTACT

- +40736039452
- carinaa.calin@gmail.com
- Bucharest-Barcelona

EDUCATION

Univeristy of Marketing and Economic Studies

2016 - 2019

University of Law

2016 - 2020

SKILLS

- Management Skills
- Digital Marketing&Advertising
- Successful Negotiation
- Critical Thinking
- Leadership
- Research and data analysis
- Professional decision-making in a fast-paced environment
- Communication
- ActiveListening
- Motivational Ledeship
- Strategic Thinking
- Business scale-up

ABOUT ME

A professional with 16 years Sales experience, deep knowledge of Startups, SaaS, ATL & BTL, Account Management, Project Management, Advertising, Lead Generation and Client Service, in areas of business from the luxury sector mass-market, real estate, FMCG, SaaS and advertising.

EXPERIENCE

Account Executive& Affiliate Sales

2020 - 2024

WeLearn - Nordic UKI

- Solving problems for clients by understanding and exceeding their expectations
- Overseeing and achieving quota, organizational goals while upholding best practices
- Participating in brainstorming, office activities, staff meetings, and client meetings; research and assist with program development for existing clients and new prospects
- · Performing prospecting activities such as cold calling and networking
- Following up with clients regularly to ensure needs are being met and to identify opportunities
- Maintaining a database of clients, prospects, partners, and vendors

Regional Sales and Business Developer

2020 - 2023

Whistlesystem - Eastern Europe

- Creating and executing a territory sales plan that meets or exceeds established sales quotas and supports company revenue and profit targets with new market strategic entry
- Continuous competitor surveillance and ability to use this as insight to prioritize sales activities
- Developing an in-depth knowledge of the Whistlesystem brand portfolioof products and services through successful completion of sales training; utilize knowledge to successfully sell products to new and existing customers in the assigned Territory.
- Manage assigned B2B customer territory by prioritizing customer visits to capitalize on sales

Working closely with the business development team to maximize selling time in the field

• Complete sales activity reports and presentations in a timely manner, including a Territory Monthly Report

LANGUAGE

English C2
German B2
Romanian C2

TOOLS

Salesforce

Hubspot

CRM

Slack

Ms Office

Excel

Adobe

CRM

SRT

BID

IDD

Business Manager

Avaya

Team Leader Outbound-Inbound &AE

META (Facebook) UKI Nordic US

- Leading a sales team of 12 Senior SDRs, building, trained and enabled analysts and reps around product knowledge, operational processes, best practices with tech stack and outbound strategies
- Teleperformance, outbound calling B2B or B2C sales, business development, inbound lead flow
- Sales and marketing, business manager analysis, ad placement optimization, digital advertising, digital marketing, online marketing
- Data analysis, data operation, multinational client management,
- Analytics (data-driven targets)
- Present products to prospective clients; regular contact with clients to understand and meet their needs
- Manage the entire sales cycle from finding a client to securing a deal
- Developing sales strategies and setting quotas
- Maintaining a database of contact information
- Following up with prospects several times throughout the sales cycle to ensure needs are being met

Account Executive

2015-2020

2020 - 2022

QUARTET AGENCY Eastern Europe

- Creating detailed business plans to reach predetermined goals and quotas
- Upselling and cross-selling
- Managing the entire sales cycle from finding a potential client to
- Securing business opportunities and negotiating contracts
- Discovering new sales opportunities through networking and turning them into long-term partnerships
- New business, market research, sales, pitching and delivering client strategy development
- Advertising, budget development for clients
- Sourcing new sales prospects and reaching out to them
- Developing customized pitches for different target accounts and personas, building new business relationships, connecting with new customers

Account Manager

2011-2015

HIPPOS AGENCY

- Developing integrated campaign strategies that incorporate ATL and BTL elements
- Overseeing the execution of advertising campaigns from concept to completion
- Collaboratig with other internal and external teams to create ATL and BTL campaigns that align with client goals
- Monitor campaign performance, analyze data, and provide regular reports to clients, making recommendations for campaign optimization
- Building and maintaining strong client relationships and identify opportunities for account growth
- Staying updated on industry trends and innovations in both ATL and BTL
- Managing budgets, timelines, and project deliverables to ensure seamless execution of campaigns
- Seeking new leads & clients to add to the company portfolio

CLIENTS

Love, Beauty & Planet

Schmidt's Naturals

7 Generation,

Unilever

British American Tobacco

MINI

Sephora

Milka

Jägermeister

Zepter

Lenor

Dero

Telekom Electronic Beats

Moet et Chandon

Absolut Vodka

Telekom Romania

Danone

Hyundai

Heinz

CELLINI

Porsche

UNICEF

Netflix

Inditex

Valentino S.p.A

Account Manager

Leo Burnett

 Collaborating with clients to understand their marketing campaign goals and objectives

- Developing integrated campaign strategies that incorporate ATL and BTL elements
- Creating comprehensive campaign briefs and project timelines.
- Overseeing the execution of advertising campaigns from concept to completion
- Managingand nurturing client relationships, serving as their primary point of contact
- Working closely with creative, design, and production teams to ensure campaign deliverables meet client expectations
- Monitoring campaign performance and provide insightful analysis and recommendations for improvements.

Startupfounder and CEO

2013-2020

Detox+Market Buy Local

- Luxury fashion start-up focused on B2B and B2C
- Scaling from 2-500 vendor event
- Outdoor campaigns and International Collaborations
- Developing and executing strategic plan to achieve sales targets and expand our customer base
- Building solid relationships with customers, vendors and distributors, as well as sales and marketing teams
- Developing in-depth knowledge of company offerings to identify profitable business opportunities
- Researching emerging trends and recommending new company offerings to satisfy customers' needs
- Developing and managing strategic partnerships to grow business
- Developing a strong business plan for investors
- Building and maintaining strong, long-lasting customer relationships
- project and team management; talent acquisition, business strategy, business development, marketing, event planning & management, sales, PR
- financials (accounting, controlling, budget planning), client service

Store Manager

2009-2013

Valentino S.p.A

- Trend research, marketing, sales, promotions, visual merchandising
- Operational procedures, client service, people management
- Escalation management, employee training, budget management
- Annual sale reports, shop inventory.

2014-2015